Okay, so I'm going to tell you how to avoid taxes, legally, of course.
So if you work a remote job in the US, you're paying more in taxes than you legally have to.
This isn't some loophole for rich people.
This is the biggest tax break for the common man.
If you work a remote job, if you make less than $126,000 in the year 2026,
you could owe zero in federal taxes.
This is something that the government doesn't tell you has no incentive to.
But this law has been around since 100 years ago, 1926.
Okay, so what am I talking about?
I'm talking about foreign earned income tax exclusion.
And you might be thinking, wait, but this is foreign earned and I work in the US.
No, listen to me.
This is how it's going to apply to you.
Watch.
So what is it?
Why does it exist?
The US is one of the only two countries in the entire world that taxes its citizens no
matter where they make their money.
Out of 170 plus countries, the US is one of two.
Think about that.
If a UK citizen goes to Dubai, they're not getting taxed.
If a German goes to Thailand, they're not getting taxed.
But God forbid an American goes abroad, the IRS still wants this cut.
So what it actually is, it lets Americans who are living outside the US set aside taxes
that they don't have to pay if they make less than a certain amount.
And to qualify, you basically have to be a tax resident of another country or you have
to be physically present outside the US for more than 330 days.
So you don't renounce citizenship or you don't hide money or anything like that.
You just live somewhere else and then you file a form.
And it's one form.
It's form 2555.
People think that you have to a mountain of paperwork.
This is one form and I'll explain it.
So that's basically what it is.
If you live outside the US and you make money outside the US, you don't have to pay money
on, you don't have to pay taxes on the first one hundred and twenty thousand dollars.
But then you might be thinking, how does that apply to me?
I'm in the US, I'm an American citizen and I make my money in the US.
Well, here's the thing.
If you just leave the US or you had plans of already leaving the US, you can take advantage
of it. So let's say you make your money in the US and you're a remote employee.
And you make less than one hundred and twenty thousand dollars a year.
You don't have to pay taxes federally on the first one hundred twenty thousand dollars.
So then the goal is to leave the US or if you're already outside the US and making money
inside the US through the Internet, then you're late.
It's great. You've done everything you need to do.
OK, so that's what it is.
But then you might be thinking, isn't it foreign earned?
I can't even qualify for that because I'm making money inside the US.
Well, this is where the physical presence test comes in.
And don't worry, I'll explain.
So here's the math. OK, so let's just do a little bit of calculating.
What are the federal taxes on one hundred and twenty six thousand dollars?
OK, so for 2025, the federal income tax is on one hundred and twenty six thousand dollars.
And it's twenty thousand nine hundred and forty six.
So you don't owe those taxes for that year if you just live outside the US.
That's basically thirty thousand dollars extra in your pocket.
And the way that it works is that even let's say you make double that.
Let's say you make two hundred and forty thousand.
You're still saving thirty thousand dollars that year because it excludes the first
one hundred twenty thousand.
So it's essentially like you're making one hundred twenty thousand that year.
And that taxed is only thirty thousand.
OK, so those numbers are theoretical, right?
But here's how it worked for me, because I actually used it.
So I made two hundred and so I made two hundred and eighty thousand dollars in 2025.
And the first one hundred and twenty thousand dollars were excluded.
So I was only taxed on the whatever was remaining.
And so what's that one hundred sixty thousand dollars?
But the point is that I didn't pay thirty thousand dollars extra in taxes.
And all you really have to do is tell your employer that you're exempt from federal
taxes and you don't pay those taxes.
And then at the end of the year, you just say, oh, I'm taking the federal earned
income tax exclusion and they just say, OK, and then you just don't pay any taxes.
Right. Your employer doesn't know about doesn't have to know about what you're
eligible for or you're including or excluding in your taxes.
Their only job is to like you file a form and you say that you're exempt from taxes
and they have to file it and that's it.
So there's something on their end that they have to worry about.
Actually, let's say you use something like ADP, that software for for your job.
They use that software.
Then your employer literally can't look at that account.
They can't see any information that they have on you that or that you have in there.
So they can't really look at that account to say, oh, is he like exempt or not
exempt and stuff like that.
So, yeah, the federal side is the easy part.
Right. Now you have to worry about state taxes.
And this is the part that people miss.
And you probably should handle this before you leave.
And every state is different. There's 50 of them.
They're all different. Let's take New York, for example.
They honored the foreign earned income tax exclusion.
So you just say federal income, foreign earned income tax exclusion.
I was outside the US here. I can prove it.
They honor that. You don't have to pay New York tax.
But let's take, for example, a state like New Jersey for them.
They don't honor that.
So you have to do something else for that.
For that, you have to say that you weren't a resident of the state.
You're not a New Jersey resident.
So there's no point in paying taxes to Jersey.
And that's how you get around taxes for those states.
So, yeah, when you file these forms, these forms are just between you and the IRS.
The employer has no way of seeing into this and seeing whatever you're doing with the IRS.
As long as you qualify for the foreign earned income tax exclusion,
you're doing nothing illegal. This is perfectly normal.
Your employer's only role is to take those W-4 forms
that say that you're exempt and file them and send them to the IRS.
That's all they need to do. OK, so those are the rules.
You have a remote job that allows you to go outside the US.
You're making money remote.
You file the form saying that you're exempt and you don't owe these taxes
so they don't get taken out of your paycheck.
Now, the question is, where do you go?
OK, so there's two strategies for this.
You can go to a different country where you don't have to pay taxes
because their laws are different.
Let's give two examples here.
If you go to Dubai, they don't have any taxes.
So you don't pay taxes.
Or you go somewhere like Paraguay, where if you make taxes,
but the source is foreign earned, like from the US, you don't pay taxes on that.
Or if you don't want to go to those countries,
you can go to any country that allows you to not be a tax resident
within a certain time period.
So let me give you some example.
Colombia, where I am now, if you're not a tax resident,
if you don't stay for if you stay less than 180 days in a year.
So I can stay in Colombia for less than 180 days.
And I'm not a tax resident, so they don't want their cut out of my income.
And it's the same thing for a lot of Latin American countries like Mexico,
Guatemala, Dominican Republic, Peru.
And that's mostly where I stay.
So three to four months, I just bounce around those countries
and I don't pay taxes to any of them.
And I don't pay taxes in the US because I'm outside the US for more than 330 days.
OK, so here's the thing about foreign earned income tax exclusion.
People think that the income has to be foreign earned, as in, let's say,
you're a US citizen and the country is, let's say, in Great Britain, in England.
You make money from there or like you make money from a country
and from a company in Mexico.
Well, no, actually, the test or what determines whether or not you qualify
for this exemption is whether or not you're outside of the country,
the US, for more than 330 days out of the year.
It says nothing about where the money came from.
It doesn't matter if the money came from the US.
If you were outside the country when you made the money and that year,
any 12 month period, you were outside the United States for 330 days.
You do not owe taxes for the first one hundred and twenty thousand dollars
that you make federally.
So that's how most people can qualify for the foreign earned income tax
exclusion if they leave the US and they make money from a US company
while being outside the US.
So here's the thing.
You might be thinking that this doesn't apply to you,
but this does apply to you if you have a remote job.
And let's say you have plans of leaving the country or I'm encouraging you
to leave the country since you get other benefits being outside the country,
like nicer weather, it's cheaper and stuff like that, friendlier people.
You get to travel if that's what you're into.
But you also get to pay no taxes because if you make money
as a remote worker for a US company and you're outside the US
for more than 330 days out of the year, you don't know taxes
for the first one hundred and twenty thousand dollars that you make.
And for a lot of people, that's basically that basically means
that they don't own any taxes.
So a lot of people in the US think that they don't qualify,
but more people actually qualify than meets the eye,
because all you have to do is be outside the US for more than 330 days.
So, yeah, I wish somebody told me earlier about this,
but like this system isn't set up to tell you that these are the things
that you can take advantage of.
For example, they don't want people leaving the US,
so they don't really advertise this.
So, yeah, if this is you and you want to take advantage of this,
if you're thinking about leaving the US or you already left,
here's what to do next.
It depends on where you are in the process.
If you don't have a remote job, I highly encourage you to get a remote job,
something that you can do on your laptop.
Once you have that, just go into the HR software
that does the taxes for your company and then just file a W-4 form
that says that you're exempt for federal and state taxes.
And then also, once you've done that, plan where you're going to move.
What's going to be your strategy?
Are you moving to Dubai, Paraguay?
A no-tax country?
Or are you going to be hopping around and what's that going to look like for you?
Are you going to stay in hotels, Airbnb?
What countries? What are you going to do?
What's the work set up for you?
Or maybe you're already abroad and you literally just have to go
into TurboTax and say that you qualify for this exemption.
And that's it. That's what it is.
That's the federal earned income tax exclusion.
And more people can take advantage of it than you think.
If you have any questions, you can leave them in the comments below.
I should have some links down below to talk about how you can reach me.
If you have any more questions
and if you have any trouble setting this up, you can talk to me
through those channels and I hope you offer for good luck.